{"questions": [
    
      {
        "question": "A trader sells 10 litres of a mixture of paints A and B, where the amount of B in the mixture does not exceed that of A. The cost of paint A per litre is Rs. 8 more than that of paint B. If the trader sells the entire mixture for Rs. 264 and makes a profit of 10%, then the highest possible cost of paint B, in Rs. per litre, is?",
        "options": ["20", "16", "22", "26"],
        "answer": "20"
      },
      {
        "question": "In a circle with centre O and radius 1 cm, an arc AB makes an angle 60 degrees at O. Let R be the region bounded by the radii OA, OB and the arc AB. If C and D are two points on OA and OB, respectively, such that OC = OD and the area of triangle OCD is half that of R, then the length of OC, in cm, is?",
        "options": ["(π/4)^(1/2)", "(π/6)^(1/2)", "(π/4√3)^(1/2)", "(π/3√√3)^(1/2)"],
        "answer": "(π/3√√3)^(1/2)"
      },
      {
        "question": "The distance from A to B is 60 km. Partha and Narayan start from A at the same time and move towards B. Partha takes four hours more than Narayan to reach B. Moreover, Partha reaches the mid-point of A and B two hours before Narayan reaches B. The speed of Partha, in km per hour, is?",
        "options": ["6", "3", "4", "5"],
        "answer": "5"
      },
      {
        "question": "Two types of tea, A and B, are mixed and then sold at Rs.40 per kg. The profit is 10% if A and B are mixed in the ratio 3: 2, and 5% if this ratio is 2:3. The cost prices, per kg, of A and B are in theratio?",
        "options": ["21:25", "19:24", "18:25", "17:25"],
        "answer": "19:24"
      },
      {
        "question": "A wholesaler bought walnuts and peanuts, the price of walnut per kg being thrice that of peanut per kg. He then sold 8 kg of peanuts at a profit of 10% and 16 kg of walnuts at a profit of 20% to a shopkeeper. However, the shopkeeper lost 5 kg of walnuts and 3 kg of peanuts in transit. He then mixed the remaining nuts and sold the mixture at Rs. 166 per kg, thus making an overall profit of 25%. At what price, in Rs. per kg, did the wholesaler buy the walnuts?",
        "options": ["84", "86", "96", "98"],
        "answer": "96"
      },
      {
        "question": "Given an equilateral triangle T1 with side 24 cm, a second triangle T2 is formed by joining the midpoints of the sides of T1. Then a third triangle T3 is formed by joining the midpoints of the sides of T2. If this process of forming triangles is continued, the sum of the areas, in sq cm, of infinitely many such triangles T1, T2, T3,... will be?",
        "options": ["192√3", "164√3", "248√3", "188√3"],
        "answer": "192√3"
      },
      {
        "question": "Let ABCD be a rectangle inscribed in a circle of radius 13 cm. Which one of the following pairs can represent, in cm, the possible length and breadth of ABCD?",
        "options": ["25,10", "24,12", "25,9", "24,10"],
        "answer": "24,10"
      },
      {
        "question": "Train T leaves station X for station Y at 3 pm. Train S, traveling at three quarters of the speed of T, leaves Y for X at 4 pm. The two trains pass each other at a station Z, where the distance between X and Z is three-fifths of that between X and Y. How many hours does train T take for its journey from X to Y?",
        "options": ["10", "12", "15", "18"],
        "answer": "15"
      },
      {
        "question": "Points E, F, G, H lie on the sides AB, BC, CD, and DA, respectively, of a square ABCD. If EFGH is also a square whose area is 62.5% of that of ABCD and CG is longer than EB, then the ratio of length of EB to that of CG is?",
        "options": ["1:3", "4:9", "2:5", "3:8"],
        "answer": "1:3"
      },
      {
        "question": "Raju and Lalitha originally had marbles in the ratio 4:9. Then Lalitha gave some of her marbles to Raju. As a result, the ratio of the number of marbles with Raju to that with Lalitha became 5:6. What fraction of her original number of marbles was given by Lalitha to Raju?",
        "options": ["1/4", "1/5", "6/19", "7/33"],
        "answer": "7/33"
      },
      {
        "question": "When they work alone, B needs 25% more time to finish a job than A does. They two finish the job in 13 days in the following manner: A works alone till half the job is done, then A and B work together for four days, and finally B works alone to complete the remaining 5% of the job. In how many days can B alone finish the entire job? ",
        "options": ["16", "22", "20", "18"],
        "answer": "20"
      },
      {
        "question": "Points E, F, G, H lie on the sides AB, BC, CD, and DA, respectively, of a square ABCD. If EFGH is also a square whose area is 62.5% of that of ABCD and CG is longer than EB, then the ratio of length of EB to that of CG is?",
        "options": ["1:3", "4:9", "2:5", "3:8"],
        "answer": "1:3"
      },
      {
        "question": "Raju and Lalitha originally had marbles in the ratio 4:9. Then Lalitha gave some of her marbles to Raju. As a result, the ratio of the number of marbles with Raju to that with Lalitha became 5:6. What fraction of her original number of marbles was given by Lalitha to Raju?",
        "options": ["1/4", "1/5", "6/19", "7/33"],
        "answer": "7/33"
      },
      {
        "question": "When they work alone, B needs 25% more time to finish a job than A does. They two finish the job in 13 days in the following manner: A works alone till half the job is done, then A and B work together for four days, and finally B works alone to complete the remaining 5% of the job. In how many days can B alone finish the entire job? ",
        "options": ["16", "22", "20", "18"],
        "answer": "20"
      },{
        "question": "Points E, F, G, H lie on the sides AB, BC, CD, and DA, respectively, of a square ABCD. If EFGH is also a square whose area is 62.5% of that of ABCD and CG is longer than EB, then the ratio of length of EB to that of CG is?",
        "options": ["1:3", "4:9", "2:5", "3:8"],
        "answer": "1:3"
      },
      {
        "question": "Raju and Lalitha originally had marbles in the ratio 4:9. Then Lalitha gave some of her marbles to Raju. As a result, the ratio of the number of marbles with Raju to that with Lalitha became 5:6. What fraction of her original number of marbles was given by Lalitha to Raju?",
        "options": ["1/4", "1/5", "6/19", "7/33"],
        "answer": "7/33"
      },
      {
        "question": "When they work alone, B needs 25% more time to finish a job than A does. They two finish the job in 13 days in the following manner: A works alone till half the job is done, then A and B work together for four days, and finally B works alone to complete the remaining 5% of the job. In how many days can B alone finish the entire job? ",
        "options": ["16", "22", "20", "18"],
        "answer": "20"
      },
      {
          "question": "In an examination, the maximum possible score is N while the pass mark is 45% of N. A candidate obtains 36 marks, but falls short of the pass mark by 68%. Which one of the following is then correct?",
          "options": ["N ≤ 200", "243 ≤ N ≤ 252", "N > 253", "201 ≤ N ≤ 242"],
          "answer": "243 ≤ N ≤ 252"
        },
      {
          "question": "Let x, y, z be three positive real numbers in a geometric progression such that x < y < z. If 5x, 16y, and 12z are in an arithmetic progression, then the common ratio of the geometric progression is?",
          "options": ["1/6", "3/6", "3/2", "5/2"],
          "answer": "3/2"
     },
      {
          "question": "If log₂(5+ log₃a) = 3 and log₅(4a + 12 + log₂b) = 3, then a + b is equal to?",
          "options": ["32", "59", "67", "40"],
          "answer": "67"
        },
        {
          "question": "Humans and robots can both perform a job but at different efficiencies. Fifteen humans and five robots working together take thirty days to finish the job, whereas five humans and fifteen robots working together take sixty days to finish it. How many days will fifteen humans working together (without any robot) take to finish it?",
          "options": ["40", "32", "36", "45"],
          "answer": "32"
        },
        {
          "question": "In a parallelogram ABCD of area 72 sq cm, the sides CD and AD have lengths 9 cm and 16 cm, respectively. Let P be a point on CD such that AP is perpendicular to CD. Then the area, in sq cm, of triangle APD is?",
          "options": ["18√3", "24√3", "32√3", "12√3"],
          "answer": "32√3"
        },
        {
          "question": "In a circle, two parallel chords on the same side of a diameter have lengths 4 cm and 6 cm. If the distance between these chords is 1 cm, then the radius of the circle, in cm, is?",
          "options": ["√13", "√14", "√11", "√12"],
          "answer": "√13"
        },
        {
          "question": "If among 200 students, 105 like pizza and 134 like burger, then the number of students who like only burger can possibly be?",
          "options": ["26", "23", "96", "93"],
          "answer": "93"
        },
        {
          "question": "In an apartment complex, the number of people aged 51 years and above is 30 and there are at most 39 people whose ages are below 51 years. The average age of all the people in the apartment complex is 38 years. What is the largest possible average age, in years, of the people whose ages are below 51 years?",
          "options": ["25", "26", "27", "28"],
          "answer": "28"
        },
        {
            "question": "The real root of the equation 26x + 23x+2 - 21 = 0 is",
            "options": ["log23/3", "log29", "log27/3", "log227"],
            "answer": "log23/3"
          },
          {
            "question": "The average of 30 integers is 5. Among these 30 integers, there are exactly 20 which do not exceed 5. What is the highest possible value of the average of these 20 integers?",
            "options": ["4", "5", "4.5", "3.5"],
            "answer": "4.5"
          },
          {
            "question": "Let a, b, x, y be real numbers such that a² + b² = 25 , x² + y² = 169 and ax + by = 65. If k = ay - bx, then?",
            "options": ["k = 0", "k > 5/13", "k = 5/13", "0 < k <= 5/13"],
            "answer": "k = 0"
          },
          {
            "question": "In a triangle ABC, medians AD and BE are perpendicular to each other, and have lengths 12 cm and 9 cm, respectively. Then, the area of triangle ABC, in sq cm, is?",
            "options": ["80", "68", "72", "78"],
            "answer": "72"
          },
          {
            "question": "Let a1, a2 be integers such that a1 - a2 + a3 - a4 + (-1)n-1 an = n, for n ≥ 1. Then a51 + a52 + …. + a1023 equals?",
            "options": ["-1", "1", "0", "10"],
            "answer": "1"
          },
          {
            "question": "Two circles, each of radius 4 cm, touch externally. Each of these two circles is touched externally by a third circle. If these three circles have a common tangent, then the radius of the third circle, in cm, is?",
            "options": ["𝜋/3", "1", "1/√2", "√2"],
            "answer": "1"
          },
          {
            "question": "What is the largest positive integer such that n² + 7n + 12 / n² - n - 12 is also a positive integer?",
            "options": ["6", "8", "16", "12"],
            "answer": "12"
          },
          {
            "question": "In 2010, a library contained a total of 11500 books in two categories - fiction and non-fiction. In 2015, the library contained a total of 12760 books in these two categories. During this period, there was 10% increase in the fiction category while there was 12% increase in the non-fiction category. How many fiction books were in the library in 2015?",
            "options": ["6600", "6160", "6000", "5500"],
            "answer": "6600"
          },
          {
            "question": "A cyclist leaves A at 10 am and reaches B at 11 am. Starting from 10:01 am, every minute a motorcycle leaves A and moves towards B. Forty-five such motorcycles reach B by 11 am. All motorcycles have the same speed. If the cyclist had doubled his speed, how many motorcycles would have reached B by the time the cyclist reached B?",
            "options": ["22", "20", "15", "23"],
            "answer": "15"
          },
          {
            "question": "Let A be a real number. Then the roots of the equation x² - 4x - log2A = 0 are real and distinct if and only if?",
            "options": ["A < 1/16", "A > 1/8", "A > 1/16", "A < ⅛"],
            "answer": "A > 1/16"
          },
        
              {
                "question": "1600 satellites were sent up by a country for several purposes. The purposes are classified as broadcasting (B), communication (C), surveillance (S), and others (O). A satellite can serve multiple purposes; however a satellite serving either B, or C, or S does not serve O. The following facts are known about the satellites:\n1. The numbers of satellites serving B, C, and S (though may be not exclusively) are in the ratio 2:1:1.\n2. The number of satellites serving all three of B, C, and S is 100.\n3. The number of satellites exclusively serving C is the same as the number of satellites exclusively serving S. This number is 30% of the number of satellites exclusively serving B.\n4. The number of satellites serving O is the same as the number of satellites serving both C and S but not B.\n\nWhat best can be said about the number of satellites serving C?",
                "options": [
                  "Must be between 400 and 800",
                  "Cannot be more than 800",
                  "Must be at least 100",
                  "Must be between 450 and 725"
                ],
                "answer": "Must be between 450 and 725"
                
              },
              {
                "question": "1600 satellites were sent up by a country for several purposes. The purposes are classified as broadcasting (B), communication (C), surveillance (S), and others (O). A satellite can serve multiple purposes; however a satellite serving either B, or C, or S does not serve O. The following facts are known about the satellites:\n1. The numbers of satellites serving B, C, and S (though may be not exclusively) are in the ratio 2:1:1.\n2. The number of satellites serving all three of B, C, and S is 100.\n3. The number of satellites exclusively serving C is the same as the number of satellites exclusively serving S. This number is 30% of the number of satellites exclusively serving B.\n4. The number of satellites serving O is the same as the number of satellites serving both C and S but not B.\n\nWhat is the minimum possible number of satellites serving B exclusively?",
                "options": [
                  "100",
                  "200",
                  "250",
                  "500"
                ],
                "answer": "250"
              },
              {
                "question": "1600 satellites were sent up by a country for several purposes. The purposes are classified as broadcasting (B), communication (C), surveillance (S), and others (O). A satellite can serve multiple purposes; however a satellite serving either B, or C, or S does not serve O. The following facts are known about the satellites:\n1. The numbers of satellites serving B, C, and S (though may be not exclusively) are in the ratio 2:1:1.\n2. The number of satellites serving all three of B, C, and S is 100.\n3. The number of satellites exclusively serving C is the same as the number of satellites exclusively serving S. This number is 30% of the number of satellites exclusively serving B.\n4. The number of satellites serving O is the same as the number of satellites serving both C and S but not B.\n\nIf at least 100 of the 1600 satellites were serving O, what can be said about the number of satellites serving S?",
                "options": [
                  "At least 475",
                  "No conclusion is possible based on the given information",
                  "Exactly 475",
                  "At most 475"
                ],
                "answer": "At most 475"
               
              },
              {
                "question": "1600 satellites were sent up by a country for several purposes. The purposes are classified as broadcasting (B), communication (C), surveillance (S), and others (O). A satellite can serve multiple purposes; however a satellite serving either B, or C, or S does not serve O. The following facts are known about the satellites:\n1. The numbers of satellites serving B, C, and S (though may be not exclusively) are in the ratio 2:1:1.\n2. The number of satellites serving all three of B, C, and S is 100.\n3. The number of satellites exclusively serving C is the same as the number of satellites exclusively serving S. This number is 30% of the number of satellites exclusively serving B.\n4. The number of satellites serving O is the same as the number of satellites serving both C and S but not B.\n\nIf the number of satellites serving at least two among B, C, and S is 1200, which of the following MUST be FALSE?",
                "options": [
                  "All 1600 satellites serve B or C or S",
                  "The number of satellites serving C cannot be uniquely determined",
                  "The number of satellites serving B exclusively is exactly 250",
                  "The number of satellites serving B is more than 1000"
                ],
                "answer": "The number of satellites serving C cannot be uniquely determined"
              },{
                "question": "You are given an n×n square matrix to be filled with numerals so that no two adjacent cells have the same numeral. Two cells are called adjacent if they touch each other horizontally, vertically or diagonally. So a cell in one of the four corners has three cells adjacent to it, and a cell in the first or last row or column which is not in the corner has five cells adjacent to it. Any other cell has eight cells adjacent to it. Suppose you are allowed to make one mistake, that is, one pair of adjacent cells can have the same numeral. What is the minimum number of different numerals required to fill a 5×5 matrix?",
                "options": [
                  "4",
                  "16",
                  "9",
                  "25"
                ],
                "answer": "4"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are given an n×n square matrix to be filled with numerals so that no two adjacent cells have the same numeral. Two cells are called adjacent if they touch each other horizontally, vertically or diagonally. So a cell in one of the four corners has three cells adjacent to it, and a cell in the first or last row or column which is not in the corner has five cells adjacent to it. Any other cell has eight cells adjacent to it. Suppose that all the cells adjacent to any particular cell must have different numerals. What is the minimum number of different numerals needed to fill a 5×5 square matrix?",
                "options": [
                  "9",
                  "25",
                  "16",
                  "4"
                ],
                "answer": "9"
              }
            ]
          }
          
          
      
       
       
      
      
      

     
<<<<<<< HEAD
    
=======
    ]
  }
>>>>>>> origin/main
  